<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>HiPhish's Workshop</title><link href="http://hiphish.github.io/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://192.168.0.190:8000/grid-framework/news/categories/organisation/atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://hiphish.github.io/</id><updated>2015-11-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><entry><title>Korean Asset Store description removed</title><link href="http://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2015/11/17/no-korean/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-11-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>HiPhish</name></author><id>tag:hiphish.github.io,2015-11-17:grid-framework/news/2015/11/17/no-korean/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I don't know why I even had a Korean Asset Store presentation in the first
place, given that I don't speak Korean. I guess Unity must have auto-generated
it based on my English description. Since I cannot verify nor maintain the
information there I have removed it. So if any Korean customers are wondering
what happened, that's the reason.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="asset-store"></category></entry><entry><title>A new blog for Grid Framework</title><link href="http://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2015/11/12/new-blog/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-11-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>HiPhish</name></author><id>tag:hiphish.github.io,2015-11-12:grid-framework/news/2015/11/12/new-blog/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update:&lt;/strong&gt; Feeds are live now, see the navigator. You can even subscribe to
just a category such as &lt;em&gt;release&lt;/em&gt; for instance by navigating to that category
and using the links in the top right-hand corner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Welcome to the new blog for Grid Framework on the new website. I have migrated
all the old blog posts here as well (with all typos and everything). The old
blog is still available for the time being, but I won't post anything there
anymore.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This website has support for multiple blogs, so this blog will from now on be
used for news only. Once I have feeds working you will also be able to
subscribe to get the latests news delivered right to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That's if for now, this was the last step needed in the migration to the new
website.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary></entry><entry><title>New website</title><link href="http://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2015/10/26/new-website/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-10-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>HiPhish</name></author><id>tag:hiphish.github.io,2015-10-26:grid-framework/news/2015/10/26/new-website/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Over the last few months I have been busy redesigning the website and we are
finally live now. Check it out:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/"&gt;http://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The new website has been rewritten from scratch, but all the old links are
still valid. It is now a modern site that looks good on desktops, on tablets,
on phones and even in text mode. All content is static and the site works fine
with and without JavaScript enabled in your browser.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="showcase-your-work"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Showcase your work&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judging by the five-star reviews you all seem to like Grid Framework, but what
are you using it for? I want to have a showcase page on the website where I can
show off some of the games made using Grid Framework. If you want your game
featured drop me a line, include a screenshot (or give me permission to pick
one myself) and a few sentences about your game and what you used Grid
Framework for. I'm looking forward to seeing all the cool uses you came up
with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class="section" id="about-the-new-website"&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;About the new website&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The original website was made from hand-written HTML and CSS. While I like the
pure hands-on approach it became quickly apparent that that wouldn't cut it in
the long run. Take for example the navigation bar: It has to appear on every
page, it has to be the same everywhere and the currently active item has to be
highlighted. HTML has no interactive elements and no way to include snippets. I
could have used JavaScript, but then the site would break down it people don't
have JavaScript enabled.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was looking into different solutions and settled for Pelican. Pelican is a
static site generator, meaning you write template HTML pages with placeholders
and you write your content separately. Pelican then generates the finished
website from your template, content and a number of settings. This has all the
benefits of being static while being easy to maintain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the actual website I decided instead of reinventing the wheel I would just
leverage the work of people who know more about web development than me. I use
Bootstrap as my CSS framework and jQuery for light JavaScript decoration. I
also now have a proper gallery using Pretty Photo library. You can find a list
of all components on the &lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hiphish.github.io/about"&gt;about&lt;/a&gt; page.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One final note about JavaScript if you are concerned about proprietary code:
all the foreign code is free software and the code I have written is free as
well (MIT licensed), no need to worry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What is still missing is the blog. Because I intend the Workshop to be home to
all my projects it would be a bad idea to lump all news into the same blog.
Pelican has no capability of producing multiple blogs, I will have to write a
multiblog plugin instead. Until then this blog stays the news site.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</summary><category term="old-blog"></category></entry><entry><title>Playable examples</title><link href="http://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2015/01/27/playable-examples/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-01-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>HiPhish</name></author><id>tag:hiphish.github.io,2015-01-27:grid-framework/news/2015/01/27/playable-examples/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;I have added playable builds of the examples to the website, now you can click
the title of an example and try the result out in the Web Player. To get back
click on the &lt;em&gt;Grid Framework examples&lt;/em&gt; label above the player. Just remember
that you have to click into the player to get it to accept input.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out the web pages:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/examples/"&gt;http://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/examples/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="old-blog"></category><category term="example"></category></entry><entry><title>A homepage for Grid Framework</title><link href="http://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2015/01/16/homepage/" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2015-01-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated><author><name>HiPhish</name></author><id>tag:hiphish.github.io,2015-01-16:grid-framework/news/2015/01/16/homepage/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Grid Framework now has its own homepage:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="http://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/"&gt;http://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have been running this blog now for almost three years, which is way too long
to go without a proper website. Back when I had just started out I didn't know
if Grid Framework would ever take off, so I organised everything in a quick &amp;amp;
simple manner, but I think it's finally time to step up my presentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The site is hosted on GitHub, so you can browse the source code if you wish,
it's all handwritten in HTML and CSS, nothing fancy. There are still a few
things I would like to overhaul, like a proper screenshot gallery, playable
examples and redo the videos. But for now the site is at least presentable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you have any suggestions or find display errors on some devices please let
me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary><category term="old-blog"></category></entry></feed>