<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Grid Framework News</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/</link><description>News for the Grid Framework plugin for Unity3D</description><language>en</language><docs>https://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Jan 2019 01:05:39 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>For those who are having build errors</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2019/01/23/build-errors/</link><description>I have been informed that some users are getting compiler errors when building
a game for release. A fix has been submitted already, but as usual it will take
a while for it to get approved. If you are affected by this issue drop me a
line, the problem can be resolved withing less than a minute. This will tie you
over until the update gets approved.</description><pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>The examples on the websites are working again</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2019/01/15/examples-working-again/</link><description>The following the recent /blog/2019/01/15/a-new-ssg/rewrite of the website, interactive /grid-framework/examples/examples on my
website are working again. Click the title link of any example and you will be
taken to a page where you can try it out in the embedded Unity HTML player (it
might take a while to load, so please be patient).</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>organisation</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 2.1.7 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2018/12/01/release-2.1.7/</link><description>Grid frameworks version 2.1.7 has been approved by the Asset Store. This
release improves integration of Grid Framework with the Unity Editor's undo
system. You can now fully undo and redo any change to any grid or renderer
property.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 2.1.6 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2017/09/12/release-2.1.6/</link><description>Grid Framework version 2.1.6 has been approved by the Asset Store. This release
fixes compilation issues with the upcoming Unity version 2017.2.</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Sep 2017 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 2.1.4 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2017/03/18/release-2.1.4/</link><description>Grid Framework version 2.1.4 has been approved by the Asset Store.  This update
fixes the algorithm for finding the nearest face in a hex grid,  and it changes
how images in the documentation are handled.</description><pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2017 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Pretty examples</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2017/01/13/reworked-examples/</link><description>The presentation  of Grid Framework has  been a sore  spot in my eyes  from day
one. Primitive  shapes are good enough  when prototyping, but when  you want to
sell something you  need to have that  extra &quot;bang&quot;, or else  your product will
look like something thrown together over a weekend.</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 Jan 2017 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 2.1.1 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2016/11/08/release-2.1.1/</link><description>Grid Framework version  2.1.1 has been approved  by the Asset Store.  This is a
maintenance release  which fixes  an error about  get_dataPath  in the latest
Unity version.</description><pubDate>Tue, 08 Nov 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 2.1.0 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2016/06/30/release-2.1.0/</link><description>Grid Framework version 2.1.0 has been approved by the Asset Store. This release
brings  new  features  in making  some  previously  read-only  properties  also
writeable, fixes compiler issues in connection with Playmaker actions and makes
the code comply with the Visual Studio compiler.</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Jun 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 2.0.1 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2016/06/05/release-2.0.1/</link><description>Version 2.0.1 fixes a bug where the custom inspector of the Cylinder renderer
for polar  grids  would  not show  up.  It would  instead  display  the default
inspector generated by Unity,  which was  still functional,  but ugly and would
expose things meant for scripting only.</description><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 2.0.0 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2016/05/25/release-2.0.0/</link><description>After almost half  a year in  the making  Grid Framework  version 2.0
      has been released on the Unity https://www.assetstore.unity3d.com/en/#!/content/62498Asset Store. This is the first major
      release since the initial launch  and will make Grid Framework  easier to
      use,  more powerful and more flexible with no extra performance overhead.
      Being a major version update this breaks compatibility  with the version
      1.x releases,  but an upgrade guide is included in  the user manual.  If
      you  still cannot  upgrade to  2.0 you can still keep using 1.x, but the
      old releases will not be getting any new features anymore.</description><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Version 2.0.0 has been submitted</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2016/05/18/submitted-2.0.0/</link><description>One of the hardest  tasks when creating something is actually shipping it,  but
it's finally time now,  version 2.0 has  been submitted to the  Asset Store for
review.  After  some  last-minute  changes here  and there,  fixing  typos  and
re-adjusting screenshots I think we are good to go.  I still have to figure out
how to set up the Upgrade option in the Asset Store, but it can't be that hard.
The submission  process officially takes  between five to ten working days,  so
hopefully the new version will be up soon.</description><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.9.1 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2016/05/13/version-191/</link><description>We are almost  at version 2.0,  but version 1.x  has not been forgotten.  In my
previous post  I was  discussing how  version 2.0  will be  distributed as  one
directory,  including the documentation.  The abuse of the WebPlayerTemplates
directory has been a thorn in my side since the start, and since the problem is
solved for version 2.0 I have applied the same fix.</description><pubDate>Fri, 13 May 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Documentation dilemma solved</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2016/05/06/docs-solved/</link><description>I have finished the build system,  which also includes the previously discussed
documentation dilemma.  The problem was the presence of actual JavaScript files
which Unity kept confusing for UnityScript files, because Unity keeps referring
to UnityScript as JavaScript.</description><pubDate>Fri, 06 May 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Fixing what has been broken</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2016/04/22/fixing-broken/</link><description>A quick  status update,  all the  examples and  the align  panel that  had been
broken by the  API change are  working  now again.  As I had  mentioned  when I
outlined the  plans for version 2.0,  this update  will break the API.  A major
version bump is an  opportunity to throw out old cruft,  decouple what does not
belong together and streamline everything that can be made simpler.</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>One unified directory</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2016/04/20/one-directory/</link><description>In version  1.x Grid Framework  has been distributed  over several directories:
Plugins,  Editor,  WebPlayerTemplates  and  GridFamework.  I  did  this
because  it seemed  logical to  split the  content by purpose,  but some people
disagreed with my choice,  so for version 2.0  everything will unify everything
in one directory.</description><pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Managing renderers</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2016/04/13/managing-renderers/</link><description>Breaking the rendering  task out of the grid  into its own dedicated class is a
good first step, but if all we have gained from this is several smaller classes
we haven't  really gained much.  In this entry  I will discuss  how version 2.0
gives you more control over the rendering process.</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Apr 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Revisiting coordinate systems</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2016/03/29/revisiting-coordinate-systems/</link><description>There are  basically two types  of grid in Grid Framework: 3D grids and layered
grids.  3D grids use all three dimensions,  these are rectangular and spherical
grids,  while layered grids are 2D  grids stacked  on top of  each other  for a
third dimension.  In this  post I  will explain  how the  coordinate systems of
layered girds will change in version 2.0.</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Official extension methods</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2016/03/05/official-extensions/</link><description>If you have been  following my updates  in regards to version 2.0 you will have
noticed that  one of the themes  has been slimming  down the API.  Some things,
such as the renderGrid flag are easy to replace  with something  more general
or trivial to  replicate with one or  two lines of code.  Other methods however
are non-trivial to implement,  useful to have and general enough to included in
the framework.</description><pubDate>Sat, 05 Mar 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Keeping the renderers updated and efficient</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2016/02/02/keeping-renderers-updated/</link><description>Rendering a grid is a three-step process: first we count how many lines we need
to render and  allocate the space needed,  then we compute their end points and
finally we send them to Unity to do its thing. In the earliest versions of Grid
Framework these three  steps had been done every frame.  Since arrays in C# are
heap objects this would send the garbage  collector in overdrive for very large
grids.</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Namespaces for everything</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2016/01/25/namespace-everything/</link><description>Releasing a new major  version is a good  opportunity to  say goodbye  to older
versions of your environment.  Version 2.0 will require at  least Unity version
5.0, which will free me from the restrictions of previous versions.</description><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>First major step towards 2.0</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2016/01/13/first-step-to-2.0/</link><description>I have  now finished the first major task  towards version 2.0:  extracting the
renderers into their  own class.  Until now the  task of rendering the grid was
part of the grid class, this made the classes much larger and it was impossible
to add one's own rendering shapes without modifying the grids themselves.</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>What's coming in 2016</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2016/01/02/new-year-2016/</link><description>It's the start of a new year, time to look back and look ahead. 2015 has
      seen the release of the new website, which was later that same year
      scrapped completely for a yet another website. I was also able to finally
      integrate the last of the originally planned grids into Grid Framework.</description><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jan 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>organisation</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.9.0 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2015/12/14/version-190/</link><description>Version 1.9.0 of Grid Framework has been approved by the Asset Store team. This
release  marks  the addition  of  the fourth  kind  of  grid to  the framework:
spherical grids.</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 Dec 2015 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Spherical grid coordinate systems</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2015/11/30/spheric-coordinate-systems/</link><description>Progress has been better than expected and spheric grids are practically done.
This is a good opportunity to take a look at the coordinate systems in spheric
grids.</description><pubDate>Mon, 30 Nov 2015 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Spheric grid rendering</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2015/11/27/spheric-rendering/</link><description>I have been working on the next type of grid: spheric grids. Think latitude and
longitude like on Earth. Here is a GIF of a rendered grid rotating around its
axis. Don't worry about the framerate, that's how the image was recorded to
save space, the actual rotation is smooth as silk.</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2015 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.8.4 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2015/11/23/version-184/</link><description>Version 1.8.4 of Grid Framework has been released. This version updates
Vectrosity support to Vectrosity version 5, and it also changes how support for
other plugins is enabled. It also introduces a new example: an endless grid in
3D space.</description><pubDate>Mon, 23 Nov 2015 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Korean Asset Store description removed</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2015/11/17/no-korean/</link><description>I don't know why I even had a Korean Asset Store presentation in the first
place, given that I don't speak Korean. I guess Unity must have auto-generated
it based on my English description. Since I cannot verify nor maintain the
information there I have removed it. So if any Korean customers are wondering
what happened, that's the reason.</description><pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>organisation</category></item><item><title>A new blog for Grid Framework</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2015/11/12/new-blog/</link><description>Update: Feeds are live now, see the navigator. You can even subscribe to
just a category such as release for instance by navigating to that category
and using the links in the top right-hand corner.</description><pubDate>Thu, 12 Nov 2015 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>organisation</category></item><item><title>New website</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2015/10/26/new-website/</link><description>Over the last few months I have been busy redesigning the website and we are
finally live now. Check it out:</description><pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>organisation</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.8.0 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2015/03/11/version-180/</link><description>Version 1.8.0 of Grid Framework has been approved by the Asset Store team. This
release introduces a new rendering shape for hex grid: the circle. Of course,
like with polar grids, just because it's called a circle that does not mean you
are limited to just circles, you can decide on the start and end &quot;angle&quot; or
have a hole in the centre to create a ring.</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2015 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.7.4 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2015/03/01/version-174/</link><description>Grid Framework version 1.7.4 has been approved by the Asset Store team. This
release brings official support for Unity 5, so feel free to upgrade. Unity 4
is still supported, thanks to the changes to the Asset Store I can now upload
separate packages for different versions of Unity.</description><pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2015 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Playable examples</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2015/01/27/playable-examples/</link><description>I have added playable builds of the examples to the website, now you can click
the title of an example and try the result out in the Web Player. To get back
click on the Grid Framework examples label above the player. Just remember
that you have to click into the player to get it to accept input.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>organisation</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.7.2 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2015/01/21/version-172/</link><description>Version 1.7.2 of Grid Framework has been approved by the Asset Store team. This
release and the previous one provide bugfixes:</description><pubDate>Wed, 21 Jan 2015 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>A homepage for Grid Framework</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2015/01/16/homepage/</link><description>Grid Framework now has its own homepage:</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Jan 2015 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>organisation</category></item><item><title>Goodbye MonoDevelop, hello Vim</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2015/01/09/hello-vim/</link><description>One thing that has been getting on my nerves ever since I started working with
Unity has been MonoDevelop. While it is a good IDE for the most part it
suffered from a number of annoying issues, such as folds randomly opening, poor
performance, and auto completion randomly not working. Your mileage may vary,
and for the most parts it was doing its job, but the annoying hiccups kept
happening all the time.</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Jan 2015 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.7.0 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2014/12/11/version-170/</link><description>Version 1.7.0 of Grid Framework has just been approved by the Asset Store team.
This release brings some more love for hexagonal grids in the form of two new
coordinate systems and four new rendering shapes.</description><pubDate>Thu, 11 Dec 2014 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.5.3 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2014/11/07/version-153/</link><description>Grid Framework version 1.5.3 has been approved by the Asset Store team. This
release brings compatibility with the upcoming Unity 5.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Nov 2014 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.5.2 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2014/11/06/version-152/</link><description>Grid Framework version 1.5.2 has just been approved of by the Asset Store team.
This release is a bugfix for polar grids where the cylindrical lines have not
been calculated properly if the depth of the grid was not 1.</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Nov 2014 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.5.1 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2014/10/01/version-151/</link><description>This release is a hotfix for everyone who was using Playmaker</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Oct 2014 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.5.0 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2014/09/16/version-150/</link><description>Grid Framework version 1.5.0 has been approved by the Asset Store team. This
version brings a great new feature for anyone interested in making isometric 2D
games: shearing. Shearing allows you to slant a rectangular grid's axes without
having to rotate the grid. Up until now the only way to achieve the isometric
look was to rotate the grid or the camera in 3D space, but in 2D games the
camera has to be perpendicular to the image plane and thus the grid as well.
Now all you need to do is just set the shearing of the axes and you're good to
go, everything else stays the way it was.</description><pubDate>Tue, 16 Sep 2014 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Whitelisting subdirectories in Git</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2014/09/09/whitelisting-in-git/</link><description>After having migrated the development of Grid Framework to Git I wanted to set
it up to track only certain sub-directories. I turned out that whitelisting is
quite tricky, so here is how I did it for people who might run into the same
problem.</description><pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Shearing</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2014/08/24/shearing/</link><description>As I mentioned last time the upcoming release will be a maintenance release
with some much-needed cleanup. While I'm still waiting for approval I have been
working on a new feature for rectangular grids that I had wanted to do for
quite a while now, but couldn't until the cleanup: I'm talking about shearing.</description><pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.4.1 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2014/05/09/version-141/</link><description>Actually it has been up for almost a month already, but I have been busy.
Anyway, this is the long-awaited release that brings PlayMaker support to Grid
Framework, so here is the change log:</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 May 2014 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.3.5 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2013/12/10/version-135/</link><description>Grid Framework version 1.3.5 has been approved last week, here is the
changelog:</description><pubDate>Tue, 10 Dec 2013 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.3.4 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2013/09/20/version-134/</link><description>This is a small update, it adds the ability to offset the origin of the grid.
It also adds a chapter to the manual about extending Grid Framework with your
own code. There is nothing in there experienced .NET user wouldn't know, but I
figure some user might not know about extension methods and might do things in
a hacky way, so I added the chapter to it, along with example code.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Sep 2013 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.3.3 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2013/08/28/version-133/</link><description>Grid Framework version 1.3.3 has been approved by the Asset Store team. This
update addresses a bug introduced in version 1.3.2 where values of colour
vectors (such as axisColor) and bool vectors were not persistent. Now they will
stick again. I also broke the examples for the sliding puzzle and movement with
obstacles, which are now fixed. Based upon a customer's question I also built a
snake game example; it's mostly an extension of the grid-based movement but
with several snake segments following each other.</description><pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2013 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.3.2 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2013/08/09/version-132/</link><description>Version 1.3.2 of Grid Framework has been approved by the Asset Store Team. The
biggest news is the  addition of new coordinate systems for hexagonal grids.
You have cubic coordinates, rhombic coordinates and the old odd herringbone
coordinates now. Even herringbone and barycentric coordinates will be added at
some point in the future for the sake of completion, but they are no priority.</description><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2013 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Status update and Doxygen rant</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2013/08/02/status-update/</link><description>It has been two weeks since my last update, so I wanted to let you guys know
what I am currently at. The good news is that the new coordinate systems have
been implemented and are ready to use. Of course there is still the obligatory
last check to do, but i expect everything to be fine. All methods that got the
axe are now gone as well and have been put into extension methods and ZIPped
into archives; that way no one will accidentally use the deprecated API. I also
added a section called Legacy Support to the manual with instructions.</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Aug 2013 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>What's up next?</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2013/07/19/whats-up-next/</link><description>Hello everyone, I decided to do a status update so you know what's going on and
coming next.</description><pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2013 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>CheckComponent()</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2013/07/03/check-component/</link><description>Here is a quick but handy tip. Recently I found myself needing to reference
various components in my script without knowing if they exist. I have to get
the component and then check if it exists, and if not add it to prevent null
exceptions. Here is what you would write in such a case:</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Jul 2013 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.3.0 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2013/06/17/version-130/</link><description>Grid Framework version 1.3.0 has been approved by the Asset Store team. The
biggest features of this release is the addition of polar grids. Check out the
updated included examples to see them right in action. Notice how in the
lights-out example the coordinates wrap around, meaning that once you've
exceeded the maximum angle it start from the beginning again without you having
to worry about anything.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2013 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Version 1.3.0 submitted</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2013/06/12/version-130-submit/</link><description>A quick heads-up, version 1.3.0 has finally been submitted to the Asset Store.
Remember, the price will go up to 25$, so if you still want it for 20$ now is
the time to buy.</description><pubDate>Wed, 12 Jun 2013 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Feature freeze for polar grids</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2013/06/09/feature-freeze-polar/</link><description>Here is a quick update: I have reached feature freeze for polar grids, meaning
I'm done with all the features. Now I need some last polish and I must prepare
new images for the Asset Store, then it's all good to go. So, what took me so
long? Well, designing and writing code is one thing, then you have to put it to
use This often reveals weak points, some things might seems counter-intuitive,
or some things are more complicated to use than others.</description><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jun 2013 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Polar grid drawing refined</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2013/05/26/polar-drawing/</link><description>Hello again</description><pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2013 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.2.5 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2013/05/17/version-125/</link><description>This release serves as a preparation for Version 1.3.0, which will add polar
grids</description><pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2013 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>A first look at polar grids</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2013/05/10/first-look-polar/</link><description>I've been working on the next type of grid: polar grids. The http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Polar_coordinatespolar
grid is based on polar
coordinates, meaning instead of identifying a point's position using X and Y
coordinates we use a radius and an angle. The radius tells us how far from the
origin the point is and the angle tells us the direction. This screenshot shows
the new polar grid in Unity</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2013 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.2.4 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2013/04/03/version-124/</link><description>Version 1.2.4 has been approved by the Asset Store team. Here are the new
features:</description><pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2013 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Seemingly endless grids and performance</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2013/03/30/endless-grid/</link><description>I've been dealing with performance in Grid Framework recently and added a
feature that will keep the Garbage Collector from going crazy. Until now
rendering always went like this: Manager requests rendering from grid -&gt; grid
calculates the end points of each line -&gt; these points get passed to Unity's GL
class for rendering. Every single frame. I have introduced a caching feature
that will store all the calculated points and reuse them instead of calculating
everything all over again as long as the grid has not been modified.</description><pubDate>Sat, 30 Mar 2013 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>tips</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.2.3 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2013/02/28/version-123/</link><description>This update brings you two new features, both were suggested by customers. The
first one is the ability to set a separate set of colours for rendering instead
of using the same colours as for drawing. Let's say you want a barely visible
grid in the game but a clearly visible grid in the editor. Until now you either
had had to have two grids or use a script to change the colours once the game
starts. Both options worked fine but required more work than needed, now you
can do it out of the box. Of course it is entirely optional, so if you don't
set anything you will be using the same colours for rendering and drawing.</description><pubDate>Thu, 28 Feb 2013 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Unity and properties/accessors</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2013/02/14/properties-accessors/</link><description>As mentioned in the previous post I'd like to relate my experience with using
properties in Unity and how to make them work properly. Properties are a C#
feature and not available in UnityScript (another reason to ditch UnityScript).
To help demonstrate what I mean I will be using a &quot;circle&quot; class.</description><pubDate>Thu, 14 Feb 2013 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.2.2 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2013/02/12/version-122/</link><description>Update time. Let's go over what's new:</description><pubDate>Tue, 12 Feb 2013 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Happy new year</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2013/01/01/new-year/</link><description>A happy new year to everyone! This has been quite a year for me, so what better
opportunity to recap the birth process and evolution of Grid and set the plans
for this year?</description><pubDate>Tue, 01 Jan 2013 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>How to extend Grid Framework with your own methods</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/12/24/how-to-extend/</link><description>Let's say you just bought Grid Framework, wrote some game logic and now you
want to reuse it. Wouldn't it be great if it was a class method in Grid
Framework so you could simply call it with one line of code? Even better, what
if you could have one method that has the same syntax for both rectangular and
hexagonal grids but different implementation based on the type of grid, so you
would have to write just one script for any type of grid? Luckily this is no
problem in Unity thanks to extension methods and if you have the code, then
wrapping it up into an extension method can de done in a few minutes. Take a
look at my latest video tutorial:</description><pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>tips</category></item><item><title>Hex Grid introduction video</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/12/17/hex-intro/</link><description>I made a short video giving you an overview of hex grids, so you can see them
right in action. I'll make a video on how to extend Grid Framework with your
own methods yourself next,</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Dec 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.2.0 submitted</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/12/07/version-120-submitted/</link><description>Just a quick update, version 1.2.0 has been submitted. This is your last chance
to buy the package for 15$, once it has been approved the price will be raised
to 20$.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.2.0 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/12/07/version-120/</link><description>The wait is over, version 1.2.0 is out, bringing you the long promised hex
grids. I'll soon make a video demonstrating the new grid, in the meantime let
me explain it in words. My implementation brings you all the features you knew
from rectangular grids, except on a hex grid, and both grids inherit from the
same base class. This means the API for both is the same and you can write one
script for both grids with little to no need to make special adjustments for
different grid classes. Currently there is only one coordinate system and hex
grids have &quot;only&quot; as much functionality as rectangular grids. I wish to improve
upon this in the future.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.1.10 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/11/30/version-1110/</link><description>The 1.1.10 update brings in a new function, ScaleVector3(Vector scl) : Vector3
which takes in a vector and then scales it so it fits inside the grid. This is
similar to AlignVector3, which was introduced in the last update, to allow
performing the aligning and scaling without having to provide an actual
Transform.</description><pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>How about herring for lunch?</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/11/27/herring-for-lunch/</link><description>Another progress update: WorldToGrid and GridToWorld are now implemented.
For those who don't know, those two functions convert a point's coordinates
from world space to grid space, the coordinate system used to locate points
relative to the grid's properties, and back. For rectangular grids it's a
fairly simple idea, the grid can be represented as a standard Cartesian
coordinate system.  With hex grids that won't do it, you simply cannot force a
hex grid into a Cartesian coordinate system, you need to find something else.
Fortunately there are several topologically identical possibilities with
easier, more intuitive coordinate systems. For the first release I have decided
to use the herringbone pattern:</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Trying to fit a square peg into a hex hole</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/11/22/square-peg-in-round-hole/</link><description>The align feature has been giving me quite some headache lately. For small
objects it's easy, just fit them inside the nearest hex. It gets more
interesting once your object spans over more than one hex. Here is a screenshot
from the game &quot;Age of Wonders&quot; for PC (I upscaled the image manually, AoW has a
very low resolution)</description><pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Grid Framework version 1.1.9 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/11/19/version-119/</link><description>Surprise update! Version 1.1.9 just got approved and it contains quite a few
changes:</description><pubDate>Mon, 19 Nov 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>How to loop through a list and remove items</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/11/16/how-to-loop/</link><description>The other day I had the following problem: I had a list of Transfoms and I
wanted to remove the entries that met a certain condition. This is what I had
written:</description><pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Hex Grids love Vectrosity</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/11/13/hex-grids-love-vectrosity/</link><description>Good news at last, I just finished the finding functions for vertices, both in
grid space and in world space. Here is a screenshot where the yellow gizmo
indicates the vertex closest to the grey sphere.</description><pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Vertex progress</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/11/12/vertex-progress/</link><description>Good news at last, I just finished the finding functions for vertices, both in
grid space and in world space. Here is a screenshot where the yellow gizmo
indicates the vertex closest to the grey sphere.</description><pubDate>Mon, 12 Nov 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Back again</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/10/28/back-again/</link><description>I just wanted to drop a line saying I'm back to work. As I mentioned previously
I was busy with exams, so development was slowed down and during the last
couple of weeks I had to stop completely to concentrate on studies. Now that
it's over I can get back to working on the hex grid update. Currently I'm about
halfway done, maybe more. I'll keep you updated :) Finally, I'd like to thank
everyone who bought Grid Framework so far, you guys have made all this effort
worthwhile and you are the ones who allow me to go on with it. Thank you.</description><pubDate>Sun, 28 Oct 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Example video: Level Design and Text parsing in Unity3D</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/10/06/example-parsing/</link><description>I made another example video for Grid Framework, this time for the recently
introduced text parsing example. Now building new levels is as easy as writing
a few lines of plain text and you get perfect clockwork-like precision. This
opens up new possibilities for faster development, easier maintenance, easier
level editors and support for user-made content. Just take a look at how
simple, yet effective it is:</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 Oct 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Version 1.1.7 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/10/05/version-117/</link><description>Version 1.1.7 has been approved by the Asset Store team. I fixed a small typo
that prevented the menu item for adding the GFGridRenderCamera component from
working and I added two more examples,  video tutorials will follow soon. I
also redid the screenshots because the Asset Store ate my old ones somehow.</description><pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Cannot log into my account</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/10/02/cannot-log-in/</link><description>I've written two new examples, one that takes a plain text file and parses it
to create a breakout-style level based on a grid without changing the scene,
the other is a continuation of my grid-based movement example where I can place
obstacles on the grid and the sphere will not step on those squares (without
using any physics like collision and raycasts). Sadly I can't update Grid
Framework because I can't log into my account via Package Manager. My account
still works, I can log into the forums and my Publisher Administration, so the
problem must lie within the editor. I've submitted a bug report, but until then
I cannot publish updates. If you are interested in one of those two examples
please contact me over the Unity forums and I'll send you the examples,
provided that you already own Grid Framework. On a related note, it appears
that Grid Framework's product page in the Asset Store doesn't have any
screenshots. I did submit screenshots, but they don't appear for me, I don't
know if other people can't see them either.</description><pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Version 1.1.6 submitted</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/09/22/version-116/</link><description>Important Note: The classes Grid and RectGrid have been renamed to GFGrid
and GFRectGrid, you will need to change your source code accordingly.</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Sep 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Version 1.1.5 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/09/06/version-115/</link><description>As per request the custom rendering range now affects drawing as well, not just
rendering. If you are wondering why this wasn't the case before, it was a
leftover from before the custom rendering range got implemented. Originally the
custom range was only meant for rendering because that would be what the layer
sees in the final game, not the drawing, whether they are the same or not.
Also, the drawing is only a drawing, the grid keeps working beyond what's
visible, being infinite. That's why the drawing had low priority and I worked
on other parts instead.</description><pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Version 1.1.4 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/09/05/version-114/</link><description>Version 1.1.4 has been approved. It doesn't add anything new for a change,
instead it fixes a bug where lines with a width larger than 1 were drawn on top
of things they were supposed to be under.</description><pubDate>Wed, 05 Sep 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Hex grid progress so far</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/09/02/hex-grid-progress/</link><description>Here's a quick status update:</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Sep 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Hex grid drawing - finally!</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/08/30/hex-drawing/</link><description>I have finished the drawing part for hex grids. As I mentioned before, there
are many ways to draw hex grids and I want to cover as many of them as
possible. Let's count all the possibilities that work now.</description><pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Swap variables in Unity</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/08/25/swap-variables-in-unity/</link><description>I've decided to go with one HexGrid class and provide enough options. To do
this I will need to swap around variables so I can use the same formulae for
different cases. I could write the swapping part where it is needed, but then
I'd be writing the same thing several times (which is a bad thing to do).
Wouldn't it be better if there was some sort of swapping function? Could that
function work for any type of variable? Could it work without needing to
reassign variables again? Yes to all of that:</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>The current roadblock</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/08/23/current-roadblock/</link><description>It has been over a week since my last post, so I might as well explain what's
going on. As I finished rendering I had tightened up all loose ends that were
left, I consider Grid Framework to be complete for rectangular grids. You can
perform all the common calculations, debug things and visualize the grid
properly, either using simple lines or even Vectrosity. This is just the first
step though. Hex grids are very popular for games for various reasons, so it
makes perfect sense to do them next, right? Well, here is where the problem
starts.</description><pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Version 1.1.3 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/08/15/version-113/</link><description>You know, sometimes I look at something and wonder &quot;what kind of idiot designed
this!?&quot;, only this time I was the idiot. Let's say you wanted to render a
simple 3x3 grid and you wanted the origin to be in the lower left corner. Well,
you simply couldn't do that, not until now:</description><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Version 1.1.2 released</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/08/14/version-112/</link><description>It's up, version 1.1.2 brings Vectrosity support, better documentation and
integrates Grid Framework into the menu bar. From now on you will never again
have to drag scripts manually from the Plugins folder onto objects when using
Grid Framework.</description><pubDate>Tue, 14 Aug 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Vectrosity progress</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/08/12/vectrosity-progress/</link><description>Well, it's pretty much done, you can now get a set of Vector3 points for use
with Vectrosity from just one line of code. I played a bit with Vectrosity to
make an example scene and this is what it looks like:</description><pubDate>Sun, 12 Aug 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Line width for rendering</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/08/09/line-width-for-rendering/</link><description>I just submitted version 1.1.1 (update: has been approved) which lets you set
the width of the rendered line in the inspector. Here is an example, obviously
it's over the top, but you can set the width to anything you like.</description><pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Version 1.1.0 out now - rendering included</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/08/08/version-110/</link><description>Unity just approved version 1.1.0, which includes the new inspector panel and
the rendering setup. Now you can see your grid in the finished game, no pro
license or any other addon needed.</description><pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>A new inspector</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/08/07/new-inspector/</link><description>Well, I wanted to do this sooner or later anyway, so I made a custom editor for
the rectangular grid. Before this I was using the default inspector panel:</description><pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Grid rendering progress</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/08/06/grid-rendering-progress/</link><description>Take a look at this:</description><pubDate>Mon, 06 Aug 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Version 1.0.1</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/08/04/version-101/</link><description>If you tried debugging the functions FindNearestFace() or FindNearestBox() you
might have noticed that the cubes drawn didn't have the same rotation as the
grid. While it didn't change anything about the returned value (only the centre
of the cube mattered), it looked ugly. I've submitted a small update that fixes
the rotation:</description><pubDate>Sat, 04 Aug 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Grid-based game logic</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/08/03/grid-based-game-logic/</link><description>Another video tutorial, showing how to use grid-based game logic in a puzzle
game. This is the tutorial for the lights-out game I mentioned before and which
has been included with the package.</description><pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Release!</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/08/01/release/</link><description>Grid Framework has been approved and is from now available on the Unity Asset
Store for 15$</description><pubDate>Wed, 01 Aug 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>release</category></item><item><title>Grid movement and runtime snapping</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/07/29/grid-movement-and-runtime-snapping/</link><description>Well, I just sent my second submission. There are three examples included, one
showcasing grid-based movement, one showcasing how to place objects on a grid
during gameplay and the lights-out game mentioned below. I also made tutorial
videos for the first two, showcasing how you can accomplish these tasks in a
simple manner on your own:</description><pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>A quick update</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/07/27/a-quick-update/</link><description>I have been contacted by an Asset Store admin, who recommends me to include a
demo scene so users could see an end setup. I thought dragging a script onto an
object is pretty straight-forward, but I agree, a demo scene would be a really
good idea. The tricky party is coming up with good ideas; don't get me wrong, I
have plenty of ideas for actual gameplay examples, but for a demo scene I need
something more basic and at the same time more catchy. I already made a little
sphere that randomly roams a grid face by face, stays within limits and
immediately adapts to changes in the grid, all with just 32 lines of code total
(not counting whitespaces and comments). I'll come up with two or three more
nice demos, that should give a good impression of Grid Framework  in action.</description><pubDate>Fri, 27 Jul 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Almost there...</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/07/22/almost-here/</link><description>Well, it's almost done. Again. Turns out that making an asset is only half the
job, you still need to hammer out any ugly dents, polish the thing and then
change your job to become a graphic designer, a video commentator, a writer and
a salesman! What good is the best asset if you present it in such a way that
makes people not even want to take a look? I'm not claiming that I'm an expert
in any of those fields, but I believe I did a pretty good job (well, maybe my
voice work for the video could use some improvements). In a way I'm glad the
old &quot;images&quot; I had prepared for the first version are now lost forever, that
was something to turn people away forever. You cannot imagine how awful those
looked.</description><pubDate>Sun, 22 Jul 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Turn off the lights!</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/05/29/turn-off-the-lights/</link><description>Here is a nice little puzzle game made using the grid framework. When you click
a square that square and the four adjacent squares flip their color. Your task
is to turn them all off.</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>State of the game</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/05/14/state-of-the-game/</link><description>It has been over a month since I posted the introductory video and sent my
application to Unity. I never received any confirmation, so I assume it got
lost somewhere along the way...</description><pubDate>Mon, 14 May 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>progress</category></item><item><title>Introduction video</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/04/11/introduction-video/</link><description>As promised, here it is:</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Apr 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Introduction</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/04/09/introduction/</link><description>Hello everyone :)</description><pubDate>Mon, 09 Apr 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Something's coming...</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/grid-framework/news/2012/03/27/somethings-coming/</link><description>OK, let's test this new blog thing...</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Mar 2012 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item></channel></rss>