<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>HiPhish's Workshop: Blog</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/</link><description>Software projects, various thoughts and rablings</description><language>en</language><docs>https://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 21:21:21 +0100</lastBuildDate><item><title>Making LuaRocks (partially) compliant with the XDG Base Directory specification</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2020/12/29/making-luarocks-xdg-compliant/</link><description>https://luarocks.org/LuaRocks is a community-driven package manager for the https://www.lua.org/Lua programming
language. LuaRocks packages can be installed globally or in the user's home
directory, but sadly LuaRocks does not follow the https://specifications.freedesktop.org/basedir-spec/basedir-spec-latest.htmlXDG Base Directory
specification. However, with a few lines of Lua code we can fix this
shortcoming partially at least.</description><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>open-source</category></item><item><title>Making SBCL compliant with the XDG Base Directory specification</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2020/12/28/making-sbcl-xdg-compliant/</link><description>The war on dotfiles continues, this time with http://sbcl.org/SBCL. Let's see how we can make
it comply with the https://specifications.freedesktop.org/basedir-spec/basedir-spec-latest.htmlXDG Base Directory specification.</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Dec 2020 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>open-source</category></item><item><title>Making Bash compliant with the XDG Base Directory specification</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2020/12/27/making-bash-xdg-compliant/</link><description>http://www.gnu.org/software/bash/GNU Bash does not comply with the https://specifications.freedesktop.org/basedir-spec/basedir-spec-latest.htmlXDG Base Directory specification, it uses
the classical dotfiles approach where it just dumps all its files into the home
directory. It does not even have the courtesy of putting all its files in one
common ~/.bash directory. Fortunately we can coerce Bash into compliance with
a bit of effort.</description><pubDate>Sun, 27 Dec 2020 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>open-source</category></item><item><title>A Guix daemon for runit</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2020/11/20/guix-daemon-for-runit/</link><description>I use http://guix.gnu.org/GNU Guix as a secondary package manager on my system. Previously I have
been running https://kubuntu.org/Kubuntu, which uses https://systemd.io/systemd as its init system, but I have
since switched to https://voidlinux.org/Void, which uses http://smarden.org/runit/runit. Guix comes with services for
systemd and http://upstart.ubuntu.com/Upstart included, but not for runit. Let's find out how to create
a runit service from scratch.</description><pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>open-source</category></item><item><title>My computer broke down</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2020/11/15/my-computer-broke-down/</link><description>There are two types of people: those who make backups and those who will
experience a system breakdown. Fortunately I was in the former category, but it
was still a very tedious and stressful experience. Every problem is also an
opportunity to grow and throw off dead weight, so I used the opportunity to
upgrade the hardware and switch my operating system.</description><pubDate>Sun, 15 Nov 2020 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>organisation</category></item><item><title>A web page template DSL for my website</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2020/10/02/page-template-dsl-for-my-website/</link><description>In my /blog/2020/09/28/page-dsl-for-my-website/previous blog post I presented how I had come up with an embedded
domain-specific language for creating web pages in my custom static site
generator. I also mentioned the concept of “templates” in passing. Of course it
was only logical to follow the page DSL up with a custom template DSL to smooth
over the code duplication and pattern repetition.</description><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>organisation</category></item><item><title>A page DSL for my website</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2020/09/28/page-dsl-for-my-website/</link><description>I got bitten by the Lisp bug recently again, and so I decided to clean up an
ugly wart in my static site generator which I use for generating the Workshop.
The goal was to create an embedded domain-specific language (DSL) for defining
web pages.</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>organisation</category></item><item><title>Dotfiles were a mistake</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2020/08/30/dotfiles-were-a-mistake/</link><description>Unix has a clever trick for hiding a file from being displayed by the ls
command or other file browsers: just prefix the file name with a period
character. Many applications use this fact in order to place hidden files or
directories in the user's home directory, usually containing settings, cached
files, persistent data and whatever else developers might come up with. This
practice has always struck me as just plain wrong, and I am glad that my
sentiment was confirmed by Rob Pike years ago.</description><pubDate>Sun, 30 Aug 2020 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>The best language to learn programming</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2020/08/02/the-best-language-to-learn-programming/</link><description>What is the best first language when learning how to program? There have been
many opinions over the years, each with their own selling point: BASIC was
created for beginners, Python is executable pseudocode, JavaScript runs
everywhere on the web, and so on. However, I would argue that the truly best
language has been right under our nose the whole time: the Unix shell.</description><pubDate>Sun, 02 Aug 2020 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Macho, the man command on steroids</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2020/05/31/macho-man-command-on-steroids/</link><description>The Unix man command can open a manual page if you know its name, and the
apropos command can search through the manuals if you are looking for a
specific word. Let's put the two to work together into a command I like to call
macho: the man command on steroids.</description><pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2020 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>open-source</category></item><item><title>How I manage SSH connections</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2020/05/23/how-i-manage-ssh-connections/</link><description>I have a number of machines I need to connect to via the secure shell (SSH),
and typing in the IP address or host name by hand every time get tedious very
quickly. I could use an application for that, but that's bloat. Let's instead
see how we can leverage small universal tools to build an elegant solution of
our own instead.</description><pubDate>Sat, 23 May 2020 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>open-source</category></item><item><title>De-Bootsrapping the workshop, part 2</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2020/02/29/de-bootsrapping-the-workshop-part-2/</link><description>About a year ago I wrote about the /blog/2019/02/04/de-bootstrapping-part-1/first step in
de-Bootstrapping my website, where
I made my site layout independent of the https://getbootstrap.com/Bootstrap
CSS framework. I have now finally removed Bootstrap entirely from the website.</description><pubDate>Sat, 29 Feb 2020 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>organisation</category></item><item><title>Project-local Vim settings the right way</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2020/02/08/project-local-vim-settings-the-right-way/</link><description>Sometimes you want to have a set of Vim settings specific only to a certain
project. There are many tips out there how to achieve such a setup, but most of
them expose the user to serious security risks. I am going to describe the
fundamental problem and how to solve it. TL;DR: use the https://github.com/MarcWeber/vim-addon-local-vimrcvim-addon-local-vimrc
plugin.</description><pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2020 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>vim</category></item><item><title>Learn Vim Script in Y minutes</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2020/02/01/learn-vimscript-in-y-minutes/</link><description>https://learnxinyminutes.com/docs/vimscript/My article for the website https://learnxinyminutes.com/Learn X in Y minutes about Vim scripting has
been accepted; the article teaches you how to get started with Vim's built-in
custom scripting language in a very concise manner. It has been quite an
enjoyable topic to write about and I even ended up learning a few new tricks
myself.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>vim</category></item><item><title>Switching themes automatically in lightline.vim</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2019/09/21/switching-automatically-themes-in-lightline/</link><description>I have recently switched my https://neovim.io/Neovim setup to use https://github.com/itchyny/lightline.vimlightline.vim and at the
same time I was experimenting with colour schemes. Getting lightline to switch
colours along with the rest of the editor is non-trivial, but I think I have
figured it out, so I am going to share my setup.</description><pubDate>Sat, 21 Sep 2019 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>vim</category></item><item><title>What is a programmable programming language?</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2019/06/22/what-is-a-programmable-programming-language/</link><description>When I was still researching this fabled obscure language called Lisp
       one thing people kept saying about it is that “Lisp is a programmable
       programming language”, but I could never figure out what they meant by
       that. It sounds like a smug buzzword or like a gimmick from an academic
       toy language. Lisp programmers have gotten so used to metaprogramming in
       Lisp that they seem to forget that it is either an entirely alien
       concept to people, or something people have been burned by too often
       (like every C programmer).</description><pubDate>Sat, 22 Jun 2019 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Understanding 2D rotation matrices</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2019/06/20/understanding-rotation-matrices/</link><description>When I first learned about rotation matrices they appeared quite
       “magic”; if you squinted your eyes a bit it sort of made sense, and if
       you did the math you could prove that the matrix does indeed perform the
       rotation and that all the group properties are met, but none of that
       explains where that form comes from, why it works.
       In this blog post I will explore a way to derive the formula for
       rotation matrices step by step.  If you wish to follow along you need
       only basic knowledge of linear algebra and trigonometry.</description><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Introducing Guile.vim</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2019/06/17/introducing-guile-vim/</link><description>Vim has good support for Scheme, but the problem with Scheme is that every
implementation adds its own features to the language. My https://gitlab.com/HiPhish/guile.vimguile.vim plugin
aims to improve support for http://www.gnu.org/software/guile/GNU Guile by augmenting these settings. It can
attempt to detect when a Scheme file is Guile-specific and it adds syntax
highlighting for Guile-specific forms.</description><pubDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2019 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>vim</category></item><item><title>Mirroring a GitLab repository</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2019/06/11/mirroring-a-gitlab-repository/</link><description>I use https://gitlab.comGitLab to host my various https://gitlab.com/HiPhishprojects, but it is always a good idea to be
able to have an automatic mirror set up. It adds redundancy in case something
goes wrong with GitLab, and having a mirror on a popular site like https://github.comGitHub
allows people to file issues without signing up for a less popular service. I
am writing this down for myself so I don't have to figure out how to set up a
mirror every time anew. This was written for GitLab version 12.0.0.</description><pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Introducing Awk-ward.nvim</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2019/06/07/introducing-awk-ward-nvim/</link><description>In order to make writing Awk scripts easier I have written a new Neovim plugin:
https://gitlab.com/HiPhish/awk-ward.nvimAwk-ward.nvim (https://github.com/HiPhish/awk-ward.nvimGitHub mirror). This plugins allows you to edit an Awk
script or its input, and see the output live as you are making changes.</description><pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Singleton objects in Guile Scheme</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2019/05/24/singleton-objects-in-guile-scheme/</link><description>When I wrote https://gitlab.com/HiPhish/guile-msgpackguile-messagepack I needed an object to represent the nil
value, which embodies the concept of &quot;nothingness&quot; or &quot;no value&quot; in
https://msgpack.org/MessagePack. None of the existing objects like #f or '() were adequate,
so I decided to make a new one: nothing. It does not make sense for there to
be multiple instance of nothing, so it had to be a singleton. In this blog
post I will describe a way of creating such a singleton.</description><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Writing NCM2 sources</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2019/05/10/writing-ncm2-sources/</link><description>https://github.com/ncm2/ncm2NCM2 is a plugin for Neovim and Vim which provides users with a unified
completion menu. By default it displays nothing, users need to add sources
for completion. These plugins instruct NCM2 on how to get completion candidates
for a particular use-case, such as words in the current buffer, or function
names in a programming language. The NCM2 documentation explains how to write
the individual pieces of a source, and in this blog post I am going to dive
into how to connect those pieces into a working source.</description><pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2019 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>vim</category></item><item><title>Introducing ncm2-vlime</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2019/03/24/introducing-ncm2-vlime/</link><description>I have written a https://gitlab.com/HiPhish/ncm2-vlimeCommon Lisp completion
source for
https://github.com/ncm2/ncm2/NCM2, built upon
https://github.com/l04m33/vlime/Vlime. It provides asynchronous Common Lisp
completion and should work in both Vim and Neovim, depending on how well NCM2
and Vlime themselves work.</description><pubDate>Sun, 24 Mar 2019 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>vim</category></item><item><title>Implementing MsgPack.rkt, part 3</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2019/02/15/implementing-msgpack.rkt-pt3/</link><description>In the previous article we have seen how to pack an object, this time we will
see how to unpack it again on the receiving end.</description><pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>open-source</category></item><item><title>Implementing MsgPack.rkt, part 2</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2019/02/13/implementing-msgpack.rkt-pt2/</link><description>In this part of the series I want to go into how to pack data to bytes in
MessagePack. We will see how to dynamically dispatch on type and how to pack a
selection of particular types.</description><pubDate>Wed, 13 Feb 2019 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>open-source</category></item><item><title>Implementing MsgPack.rkt, part 1</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2019/02/11/implementing-msgpack.rkt-pt1/</link><description>When I originally set out to write http://docs.racket-lang.org/msgpack/index.htmlMsgPack.rkt, a https://racket-lang.org/Racket implementation of
the https://msgpack.org/MessagePack protocol, I had a hard time wrapping my mind around where to
begin. I had no experience in writing a serialisation library, and reading the
source code of existing implementations only revealed the what, but not the
why. This is why I'm starting this short mini-series of blog posts to provide
a commentary on my implementation. I hope that it will serve other people who
are looking for a starting point to their own implementations.</description><pubDate>Mon, 11 Feb 2019 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>open-source</category></item><item><title>De-Bootsrapping the workshop, part 1</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2019/02/04/de-bootstrapping-part-1/</link><description>The first major step in phasing out the bloat that is https://getbootstrap.com/Bootstrap from my
website is done. None of the layout depends on any Bootstrap classes and
markup. Instead, the layout is built from scratch using the new Flexbox and
Grid features.</description><pubDate>Mon, 04 Feb 2019 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>organisation</category></item><item><title>A pure HTML &amp; CSS menubar</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2019/01/28/pure-html-css-menubar/</link><description>In the process of de-Bootstrapping the workshop I have to replace whole
components provided by https://getbootstrap.com/Bootstrap with my own constructs. The menu bar is one
of the larger components I use, it's fairly complex and requires a lot of
non-semantic markup to get working. In this blog post I will describe step by
step how I built mine, which requires less markup and does not rely on
Javascript. You can try the demo.htmldemo to see what we are going for (please resize
your window to see the responsiveness).</description><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>organisation</category></item><item><title>Neovim channel for GNU Guix</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2019/01/21/neovim-guix-channel/</link><description>I have set up a https://gitlab.com/HiPhish/neovim-guix-channel/channel for https://www.gnu.org/software/guix/GNU Guix to build https://neovim.io/Neovim. This channel serves
as an experimental staging ground for porting Neovim (and perhaps other related
projects in the future) to the Guix functional package manager. When the
packages are deemed stable and correct enough they will be submitted to Guix
proper.</description><pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>vim</category></item><item><title>Introducing Quicklisp.nvim</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2019/01/17/quicklisp.nvim/</link><description>One of the new features of https://neovim.io/Neovim is its ability to write plugins in any
programming language, provided that there is a plugin host available. I have
wanted to play around with the https://github.com/adolenc/cl-neovim/Common Lisp host for a while, and I like for
something useful to come out of it in the end, so I created https://gitlab.com/HiPhish/quicklisp.nvimQuicklisp.nvim, a
plugin which allows users to manage Common Lisp libraries from inside Neovim.</description><pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>vim</category></item><item><title>A new static site generator</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2019/01/15/a-new-ssg/</link><description>Over two years already without rewriting the workshop? I have to rectify this,
with the greatest rewrite yet! I have abandoned Pelican because I constantly
had to adjust things manually after the build process, and even then there were
parts of the website that weren't working. This put me off from blogging, since
after each post I would have to stitch everything back together by hand. Seeing
that no static site generator would be able to meet my needs I decided to
instead write my own in Scheme.</description><pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>organisation</category></item><item><title>Goodbye macOS, hello GNU/Linux</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2018/12/01/gnu-linux/</link><description>I knew this day would come eventually, so here we are: I moved from macOS to
GNU/Linux as my operating system. It has been a couple of months since then and
I have settled in pretty comfortably; some things are better some things are
worse, and some things are just plain different.</description><pubDate>Sat, 01 Dec 2018 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>organisation</category></item><item><title>A purely functional fixed timestep loop</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2017/07/16/functional-fixed-timestep-loop/</link><description>There is a great article by Glenn Fiedler titled http://gafferongames.com/game-physics/fix-your-timestep/“Fix Your Timestep!” in
which the author explains various approaches to writing a game loop and
concludes with a loop that provides a fixed time step for simulation. If you
are not familiar with this topic go read the article first and come back later.
The author has written the implementation in C or C++ using a lot of mutation
and looping, so I wanted to give a purely functional approach a shot.</description><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2017 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Creating a mock REPL on Unix</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2017/05/13/mock-repl-unix/</link><description>During the development of https://gitlab.com/HiPhish/repl.nvim/REPL.nvim I had to be able to test the plugin
without relying on any particular REPL present on the development system. The
solution was to create a mock REPL, a shell script which acts like a really
dumb REPL. Here is the code:</description><pubDate>Sat, 13 May 2017 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Introducing REPL.nvim</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2017/05/06/introducing-repl-nvim/</link><description>Integrating a REPL in Vim has been a difficult issue in the past, but with
Nvim's built-in terminal emulator it is just a few commands away. My new
https://gitlab.com/HiPhish/repl.nvim/REPL.nvim plugin now puts the REPL only one command away, for any
programming language you wish. The end goal is to have a complete generic and
configurable REPL framework which can be customised to the needs of any
language and which forms a solid foundation for other plugins as well.</description><pubDate>Sat, 06 May 2017 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>vim</category></item><item><title>Outlining of HTML pages is fundamentally broken</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2017/04/25/html-outline-fundamentally-broken/</link><description>If you were to run the Workshop through an HTML validator you would notice a
lot of warnings about the document outline. What is going on here? HTML 5
defines an https://www.w3.org/TR/html5/sections.html#outlineoutline algorithm which allows browsers and assistive
technologies to create an outline of the page. In theory a blind person could
ask their reader for the outline of the page and get a sort of table of
contents which they could use to quickly jump to a specific part of the page.</description><pubDate>Tue, 25 Apr 2017 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Introducing info.vim</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2016/11/20/introducing-info.vim/</link><description>There is a new project up at the Workshop: https://gitlab.com/HiPhish/info.viminfo.vim, a Vim plugin which
implements a complete reader and browser for info documents from within Vim.
This is similar to the standalone info program or the Emacs info mode.</description><pubDate>Sun, 20 Nov 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>vim</category></item><item><title>Rewriting the Workshop</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2016/09/27/rewriting-the-workshop/</link><description>At this point I  could start to make rewriting  my website an annual tradition.
There have been a number of little  details that have been rubbing me the wrong
way for almost a year now;  the biggest one was the navigation bar on sub-sites
like the  Grid Framework  product site.  There were  also accessibility  issues
relating  to  the lack  of a  proper  HTML  document  outline  and  the  use of
JavaScript.</description><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>organisation</category></item><item><title>Introducing IPS-Tools</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2016/07/06/intro-ips-tools/</link><description>I found myself needing a program to apply binary patches in the IPS file format
and I was really disappointed  that there are no proper  Unix programs for that
purpose available.  So I set out to make my own,  but instead of just  applying
patches it would be a complete suite of tools to handle all IPS-related tasks.</description><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>open-source</category></item><item><title>Highlighting `NSImageView` the right way</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2016/06/25/highlighting-nsimageview/</link><description>Recently  I have  been working on  a small Cocoa  app and one  of the  things I
needed to do was highlight an  NSImageView when the user is hovering above it
while dragging a file.  You would think  that it's a very simple task,  and you
would be right, but judging by some of the things on the internet it looks like
an unsolved problem.</description><pubDate>Sat, 25 Jun 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>misc</category></item><item><title>Introducing NTFS-Clone</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2016/05/31/intro-ntfs-clone/</link><description>This is  a very  useful project  I had  written quite  a while  ago at work and
recently found collecting dust on my hard drive. It lets you create perfect 1:1
copies of NTFS hard drives on Unix.  The problem with every software I had come
across was  that it would copy the data,  but that wasn't enough,  so we had to
run Windows repair on every single drive.</description><pubDate>Tue, 31 May 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>open-source</category></item><item><title>Neovim has tab-local working directories now</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2016/04/22/neovim-tcd/</link><description>My Neovim PR to add tab-local working directories has recently been merged.  In
this post I will explain what it does and why you will love it.</description><pubDate>Fri, 22 Apr 2016 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>vim</category></item><item><title>Feeds are live now</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2015/11/14/feeds-live-now/</link><description>RSS- and Atom feeds are live now. You can subscribe to an entire blog using the
links in the navigator or you can subscribe to a particular category in a blog.
For that navigate to the category using either the navigator or by clicking the
category button of an article.</description><pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2015 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>organisation</category></item><item><title>We are live!</title><link>https://hiphish.github.io/blog/2015/11/11/we-are-live/</link><description>The Workshop blog is finally up and running, in all its static glory. This
makes the site practically complete, at least as complete as a website can ever
be anyway. It also works great with my
https://gitlab.com/HiPhish/Multiblog-PelicanMultiblog
plugin.</description><pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2015 00:00:00 Z</pubDate><category>organisation</category></item></channel></rss>