<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>HiPhish's Workshop</title><link>http://hiphish.github.io/</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://192.168.0.190:8000/blog/categories/ips-tools/rss.xml" rel="self"></atom:link><lastBuildDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><item><title>Introducing IPS-Tools</title><link>http://hiphish.github.io/blog/2016/07/06/intro-ips-tools/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;I found myself needing a program to apply binary patches in the IPS file format
and I was really disappointed  that there are no proper  Unix programs for that
purpose available.  So I set out to make my own,  but instead of just  applying
patches it would be a complete suite of tools to handle all IPS-related tasks.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a class="reference external" href="https://gitlab.com/HiPhish/IPS-Tools"&gt;IPS-Tools&lt;/a&gt; is the result, it consists of three standalone CLI programs, one CLI
program that acts as an entry point to the suite, and a C library for inclusion
in other applications. There are three programs because I have identified three
problem domains: applying a patch, generating a patch and examining a patch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The tools are all written in C99 using only the standard library, they are tiny
and  should  run  on  pretty  much  anything.  Great  for  embedding  in  other
applications.  In fact,  I have a  GUI frontend that  uses the library  to give
users a drag &amp;amp; drop interface, but it still needs some more polish before I can
release it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also took the opportunity  to write a complete specification  of the IPS file
format, because all I was able to find have been bits and pieces everywhere and
only closed-source programs, so I had to piece things together. IPS is a fairly
simple format,  but it  has some  hairy corners  because over  time people have
added  extensions  to it  (compressed records  and truncation).  With IPS-tools
there is a complete  file specification and  a reference implementation  freely
available to the public.&lt;/p&gt;
</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">HiPhish</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 06 Jul 2016 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>tag:hiphish.github.io,2016-07-06:blog/2016/07/06/intro-ips-tools/</guid></item></channel></rss>